Now.
I say welcome brothers and sisters to
another Wednesday question and answer
where we open up with the 10
Commandments that God commanded for the
whole world to keep. Brother James.
And God spoke all these words saying, I
am the Lord thy God, which have brought
thee out of the land of Egypt, out of
the house of bondage. Thou shall have no
other gods before me. Thou shall not
make unto thee any graven image or any
likeness of anything that is in heaven
above or that is in the earth beneath or
that is in the water under the earth.
Thou shall not bow down thyself to them
nor serve them. For I the Lord thy God
am a jealous God, visiting the iniquity
of the fathers upon the children unto
the third and fourth generation of them
that hate me. And showing mercy unto
thousands of them that love me and keep
my commandments. Thou shall not take the
name of the Lord thy God in vain. For
the Lord will not hold him guiltless
that taketh his name in vain.
Remember the Sabbath day to keep it
holy. Six days shall thou labor and do
all thy work, but the seventh day is the
Sabbath of the Lord thy God. In it thou
shall not do any work, thou nor thy son,
nor thy daughter, thy man servant, nor
thy maid servant, nor thy cattle, nor
thy stranger that is within thy gates.
For in six days the Lord made heaven and
earth, the sea, and all that in them is,
and rested the seventh day. Wherefore
the Lord blessed the Sabbath day and
hallowed it. Honor thy father and thy
mother that thy days may be long upon
the land which the Lord thy God giveth
thee.
Thou shall not kill. Thou shall not
commit adultery. Thou shall not steal.
Thou shall not bear false witness
against thy neighbor. Thou shall not
covet thy neighbor's house. Thou shall
not covet thy neighbor's wife, nor his
manservant, nor his maidservant, nor his
ox, nor his ass, nor anything that is
thy neighbor's. I read Exodus 20:1-17.
May the Lord add a blessing to the
reading of this word. In Jesus' name we
pray. Amen.
Amen. Amen.
For me on question and answer You can
ask us a question and we'll answer it
according to the King James Bible. And
if we cannot find the answer, we will
seek further counsel to bring you an
answer at a later time. The questions we
will not answer are the vague, as well
as the long scripture questions, and
questions of debate. We are not here to
debate. We are here to spread the true
gospel of Jesus. So, please be as direct
as possible with your questions, so we
can be as direct as possible with our
answers out of the King James Bible. No
other Bibles or books will be knowledge
during this program. Also, keep in mind
that this is a live stream, so feel free
to send in your questions that pertain
to everlasting life. We just ask that
you please keep them to a two scripture
maximum. But, let me introduce you to
family that's on the panel this evening.
We got brother Jerome.
Peace and peace.
Brother Julius.
Brother Dre.
Good evening.
Brother James. Good evening, everyone.
Sister Deborah.
Good evening.
Brother Shawn. Good evening.
And we have the guest caller with us and
our brother Cornell. Sister Deborah,
what is our first question of the
evening?
Uh yes, there are several held over
questions that will be answered first
before getting into tonight's Q&A. So,
uh
Stephen Googis asked, "What news outlets
or articles can he follow to keep watch
of the in Jerusalem to build
the temple?"
All right, the in Jerusalem and
building the temple?
What news outlets? Brother Julius.
Uh good evening, everybody. Uh there are
several news outlets. The number one is
the Bible, number one. But the the main
news outlets uh
the one that I kind of keep my eye on is
called the Jerusalem Post.
That's a very good one that keeps us
going on. You have what's called um
uh
uh CBN, which is the Christian
Broadcasting Network.
They deal with the Holy Land and events
going on over there a lot. You have um
another one called 365
uh Israel 365 News. You can write that
down. Israel 365 News. And then you have
the Temple Institute.
So, those are um
uh and Jerusalem has a newspaper called
uh The Times of Israel.
So, those are some outlets that you
could uh tune into uh
to kind of keep an eye on what's going
on in the Holy Land, but the number one
source that we use beside world news is
the Bible, Matthew 26 and verse 41.
Matthew 26 and verse 41. When you get
Can you read that for me, James? Yes, I
can. Uh-huh. It says, "Watch and pray
that ye enter not into temptation.
Uh-huh.
>> The spirit indeed is willing, but the
flesh is weak." So, that's what we do.
We we pray and we watch. Watch world
events. Watch world events, but I gave
you the ones that that I uh that I see
quite often.
So, I hope that helped, Cornell.
All right. Thank you for that
information, brother. Hope that answers
their question as we move on to our
next.
Next one. Linda Stringer says, "There
was an animal sacrifice in Israel in
2019 on Mount Olives.
Is this the beginning of the prophecy in
Daniel? This was documented in Chuck
Baldwin's Noahide Law article published
September the 26th, 2019."
All right. So, the animal sacrifice in
Israel in 2019 on the Mount of Olives,
this caller, please weigh in.
No, that's not the
That don't count.
Because uh
when the animal sacrifice start, I mean
truly start,
they will not
be stopped
until the abomination of desolation
and the nations that supporting us,
which is UN and the
the uh
which is the you know, UN
with the with the
which is Eastern Europe, Western Europe,
you know.
They will They support the Catholic
Church.
And what is is and and all the Catholic
churches is going to come to the
abomination of desolation.
So,
when they start, they will not stop
until
the
abomination is stopping. Let's go to
Daniel the 11th chapter and read verse
31.
That's the first place.
Okay.
Daniel 11
and verse 31 says,
"And arms shall stand on his part.
And they shall pollute the sanctuary of
strength, and shall take away the daily
sacrifice, and they shall place the
abomination that maketh desolate.
Now, that's when the European Union,
Western Europe
That's once they start moving, which
they will not start until they build uh
uh uh uh
uh
until uh
start until they
uh uh stop, brother. They will not stop
the animal sacrifice until they set the
abomination
up. That's why I say they should stop
the uh uh they going
stop the animal sacrifice, and they
going
place the abomination of desolation.
So, we don't the abomination of
desolation haven't even take its place
yet. A temple haven't been built.
But, to confirm that, let's go into
Daniel's 12. And we going to read verse
6 and 7 first.
Let me know when you finish 7.
Okay. Daniel 12 and 6 says, "And one
said to the man clothed in linen, which
was upon the waters of the river,
how long shall it be to the end of these
wonders?"
And I heard a man clothed in linen,
which was upon the waters of the river,
when he held up his right hand and his
left hand unto heaven, and swear by him
that liveth forever, that it shall be
for a time, times, and a half. And when
he shall have accomplished to scatter
the power of the holy people, all these
things shall be finished.
Now, a time and a time and a half, it's
talking about the 3 [clears throat] and
1/2 years that the abomination of
desolation is going to be ruled. And at
the end of that 3 and 1/2 and a half 3
and 1/2 years, it will be over with. The
Lord will be on this earth. Now, skip
down to verse 11
and read.
And from the time that the daily
sacrifice shall be taken away, and the
abomination that maketh desolate set up,
there shall be 1,290
days.
Do now. That lets you know
that when animal sacrifice start,
it's not going to stop
until the European Union come in with
the Pope
and they
move into that temple, then they're
going to stop the animal sacrifice.
So, the animal sacrifice that they did
in 2019
was just somebody up there doing
something stupid. That's all I have to
say.
All right.
Thank you for that. We hope that
answered your question as we move on to
our next question.
Maceo Victor Latrua asks, "Who is the
branch in Zechariah 3:8?"
Zechariah 3:8, the branch. Who is it,
brother Jerome?
That's That's none other than Jesus
Christ.
Yes, sir. Let's Let's go read that
Zechariah 3:8.
Okay.
It says, "Hear now, O Joshua the high
priest, thou and thy fellows that sit
before thee. For they are men wondered
at. For behold, I will bring forth my
servant, the branch."
>> [clears throat]
>> Now, let's tie this with uh Zechariah 6
chapter
and read verse 12 and 13.
Zechariah 6:12 says, "And speak unto
him, saying, Thus speaketh the Lord of
hosts, saying, Behold the man whose name
is the branch, and he shall grow up out
of his place, and he shall build the
temple of the Lord.
Even he shall build the temple of the
Lord, and he shall bear the glory, and
shall sit and rule upon his throne, and
he shall be a priest upon his throne,
and the council of peace shall be
between them both.
Yeah, he going to be a king and priest
upon his throne. And one more place,
let's tie that with Jeremiah 23.
And we going to read five and six.
Okay.
Jeremiah 23:5-6 says, "Behold, the days
come, saith the Lord, that I will raise
unto David a righteous branch, and a
king shall reign and prosper, and shall
execute judgment and justice in the
earth.
In his days, Judah shall be saved, and
Israel shall dwell safely. And this is
his name whereby he shall be called, the
Lord our righteousness." Yeah, and
that's Jesus Christ.
That's all I got on him.
All right.
Thank you for that. We hope that
answered their question as we move on to
our next.
Next one, Mike Corley asks, "Should we
pray for those who blatantly deny the
book? And John 17:9-10
are given."
All right, why don't we go to that John
17:9-10?
Sometimes those that blatantly deny the
book today might wake up
tomorrow, you never know. But let's go
John 17.
And let's pick it up, brother, at that
um
Let's pick it up at that verse six, cuz
this was Jesus having a conversation,
but he was he was talking about his
disciple
in this
particular book here. John
17, pick it up at verse six, brother.
And then we going to skip down and pick
up eight, nine, and 10.
Okay.
Verse six says, "I have manifested thy
name unto the men
which thou gavest me out of the world.
Thine they were, and thou gavest them
me.
And they have kept thy word." Yeah, so
he's talking about his disciples here,
the ones that followed him, and they
have kept their word, but also pertains
to us. We in good shape if we keep their
word, also. Skip down to verse nine and
10.
It says, "I pray for them. I pray not
for the world, but for them which thou
hast given me.
For they are thine.
And all mine are thine. And thine are
mine. And I am glorified in them."
Yes, because it was the disciples that
was keeping that word that he was
talking about.
So, skip down, brother. Um, let's go to
uh let's go to Matthew.
Let's go to Matthew.
Titus, I'm sorry. Titus three. Let's go
to Titus three.
My fault. Then we'll go
to that uh Matthew. Titus three, and
read that verse 10 and 11. Titus three,
10 and 11.
Titus three, right there. Um
You said chapter three, verse 11,
correct? 10. 10. Okay.
A man that is an heretic, after the
first and second admonition, reject. So,
you may have somebody you asked about,
you know, praying for somebody who
blatantly denied a book. Well,
sometimes when they contrary against his
word after you go tell them the first,
second time, they don't want to hear it,
then sometimes you got to fall back.
Go ahead, 11.
Knowing that he that is such is
subverted and sinneth, being condemned
of himself.
Yeah. Matthew 7 and verse 6.
Cuz you asked me about praying for him.
Hey, that's
that's your choice. Sometimes they
blatant the day, but never know what
tomorrow might bring.
Matthew 7 and 6. I read that one verse,
but prepare for this also, if they don't
want to hear that word that you
are bringing to them. Matthew 7 and read
that one verse 6 for me. Go ahead,
brother.
Give not that which is holy unto the
dogs, neither cast ye your pearls before
swine, lest they trample them under
their feet and turn again and rend you.
So, this word is holy, it's a sweet
pearl, and hey,
if they don't want to hear it and you
keep trying to bring it that way,
sometimes they would turn around and
attack you. So, just be aware of that
also, and that's all I got.
All right. We'll leave it right there as
we move on to our next one.
Next one, Victor Letcher asks,
is Zechariah 11:12
and 13 a prophecy of Jesus?
Zechariah 11:12 and 13, brother Dre,
what you say? Is that a prophecy of
Jesus? Yes. Let's go to Zechariah 11
and read verses 12 and 13.
Okay.
It says, And I said unto them, if you
think good, give me my price. And if
not, forbear.
So, they weighed for my price 30 pieces
of silver.
And the Lord said unto me, cast it unto
the potter.
A goodly price that I was prized at of
them.
And I took the 30 pieces of silver and
cast them to the potter in the house of
the Lord. So, we see the 30 pieces of
silver here.
We see it was cast to the potter in the
house of the Lord. Now, let's go over to
Matthew 26.
Matthew 26 and read verses 14 through
16.
Go ahead and get it.
Matthew 26 verses 14 through 16 says,
then one of the 12, called Judas
Iscariot, went unto the chief priest
and said unto them, what will you give
me and I will deliver him unto you?
And they convent combinated with him for
30 pieces of silver.
And from that time he sought opportunity
to betray him.
That's right. So, what they did,
Judas came to him and they coveted with
him
for 30 pieces of silver and Judas went
to betray him. Go over to 27 Matthew now
and pick it up at verse three.
27 and three says,
then Judas, which had betrayed him, when
he saw that he was condemned, repented
himself and brought again the 30 pieces
of silver to the chief priest and
elders.
Saying, I have sinned in that I have
betrayed the innocent blood. And they
said, what is that to us? See thou to
that.
And he cast down the pieces of silver in
the temple and departed, and went and
hanged himself.
He cast down in 30 pieces of silver,
and he hanged himself. He cast them down
in the temple. Go ahead.
And the chief priest took the silver
pieces and said, "It is not lawful for
to put them into the treasury because it
is the price of blood." Now, they acting
like they righteous and want to say it's
the price of blood, but they looking to
kill him. Go ahead.
And they took counsel, and bought with
them the potter's field to bury
strangers in.
Now, skip down to verse nine. Read nine
and 10, and that'll be it.
Then was fulfilled that which was spoken
by Jeremy the prophet, saying, "And they
took 30 pieces of silver, the price of
him that was valued, whom they of the
children of Israel did value,
and gave them for the potter's field, as
the Lord Lord appointed me." Now,
Jeremiah spoke about it, but Zechariah
wrote about it.
So, I hope that helps. That's all I got.
Yes, sir. Crystal clear.
All right. Hope that answered your
question as we move on to our next one.
Next one, Mike Corley says,
"Jacob lived with Laban as an adult.
Does that support that it is okay for
families' son and wife to live with
parents
due to the economy?"
All right. Jacob living with Laban and
the economy, does that justify you
still living with your parents if you
grown? Let's uh open this up to the
panel.
Because we know indeed it's getting
tough. Next caller.
Well, the first thing is
Jacob was living in the area where
in in the city where
his uncle lived. That don't mean he
lived in the same house.
That's right.
>> But
then so whether
justified for a person
live with their parent or anything
their family
because of hard times, you know, there
ain't no there is no scripture
that that denies it.
And there's no one to support it. But I
will read one thing and we can leave it
right there.
Let's go into Genesis the second chapter
and read 23 verse 23 and 24.
Okay.
Genesis the second chapter verses 23 and
24 says, "And Adam said, This is now
bone of my bones and flesh of my flesh.
She shall be called woman because she
was taken out of man.
Therefore, shall a man leave his father
and his mother and shall cleave unto his
wife and they shall be one flesh."
That's all I have to say about it.
All right.
We'll go leave it right there. Hope that
answered your question as we move on to
our next one.
Next one, then Cam asked, "Is it lawful
to begin a long journey on the Sabbath
day?"
Is it lawful to begin a long journey on
the Sabbath day? Well,
you left out where you journeying to,
but however, if you going to spread the
gospel,
then let's go to Mark 16. Mark 16.
Cuz the Israel of God travels all around
doing what does say is the Lord,
spreading the gospel to every creature.
And creatures are all over, man, woman,
and children.
Mark 16 and let's pick it up at verse 15
and 16.
Go ahead, brother.
>> He said, "And he said unto them, go ye
into all the world and preach the gospel
to every creature." So, sometime to go
into all the world requires a long
journey or journey period to get the
word out to those who may be looking for
it. 16.
He that believeth and is baptized shall
be saved. But he that believeth not
shall be damned. Uh-huh.
Pick up in 19 and 20.
So, then after the Lord had spoken unto
them, he was received up into heaven and
set on the right hand of God. And what
did the brothers do?
And they went forth and preached
everywhere, the Lord working with them
and confirming the word with signs
following. Amen. Amen. So, hey, and to
go to everywhere and throughout the
world, sometimes it requires a long
journey in order to get that word out.
But however,
if it's not dealing with the word of God
and you are traveling out of town from
one part to another on the Sabbath day,
you take the Sabbath and keeping of the
Sabbath day with you. Wherever it is
that you may go.
Because the Lord, hey, will be with us.
And that's all I got. Anybody else?
Yeah. Jerome, what you got? I wanted to
mention
take the feast days for example.
They They They high Sabbaths.
And often times you can read well, read
Acts 2 for an example. They traveled
from far countries to get to Jerusalem
to keep Pentecost, which is the Sabbath.
It's a high sign.
You know, so that's that's all I wanted
to say. Yeah. Let's by all means keep
the feast, right, brother?
Yes, sir.
All right. Thank you for that add-on. We
hope that answered your question as we
move on to our next one.
Next one, D law asked, "How do you know
that there will be a physical temple
built rather than the temple being in
our heart? That the church, the bride,
represents the temple papa will sit in
the mosque." All right. How do you know
that there will be a physical
temple rather than in your heart,
brother Julius? Because Well, let's let
the Bible tell you how do we know.
Let's let the book tell you how do we
know. Let's go to
uh
Second Peter, the first chapter, first
of all.
Let's look at what
Peter
the keys to the law left the keys of the
kingdom to what he said about it. Second
Peter 1, brother James.
And picking up at verse 16. Second Peter
1 and 16. See, this kills all the doubt.
It don't matter what we think, it
matters what's written. Go ahead.
For we have not followed cunningly
devised fables,
when we made known unto you the power
and coming of our Lord Jesus Christ, but
were eyewitnesses of his majesty. But
how do we really know? Verse 19. 19 to
21, quickly.
We have also a more sure word of
prophecy.
>> Because the prophets wrote about it. Go
ahead. Whereunto
ye do well that ye take heed as a light
that shineth in a dark place, until the
day dawn and the day star arise in your
hearts. Go ahead in verse 20.
Knowing this first, that no prophecy of
the scripture is of any private
interpretation. Uh-huh. For the prophecy
came not in old time by the will of man,
but holy men of God spake as they were
moved by the Holy Ghost. Now, it's
already written, but let's go and show
you a more perfect uh word. Let's look
at prophecy. Daniel 11 and just verse
31.
Daniel 11 verse 31 says, "And arms shall
stand on his part, and they shall
pollute the sanctuary of strength, and
shall take away the daily sacrifice, and
they shall place the abomination that
maketh desolate." This is a man that's
going to sit in the temple and profess
himself to be God. Matthew the 24th
chapter. I got one last place after
this.
Matthew 24.
We're going to put Jesus on the witness
stand. This If your Bible have you ever
read a red letter edition Bible, this is
Jesus speaking here. Matthew 24. Daniel
prophesied it. Matthew
uh uh uh it's written in Matthew. This
is Jesus. Matthew uh 24 and verse 15.
When you there
When you therefore shall see the
abomination of desolation spoken of by
Daniel the prophet stand in the holy
place. Whoso readeth, let him
understand. Also, you going to see it.
This is not talking about in the temple
of your mind. We know what 1 Corinthians
tell you that the
that the uh your body is the temple of
the Holy Spirit, but we're talking about
the we're talking about what you're
going to actually see here.
You're going to see them place the
abomination.
You can't get no more put And when you
get there, what are you going to do? My
last place. Once you get there, let's go
to 2nd Thessalonians the 2nd chapter.
2nd Thessalonians the 2nd chapter,
brother James.
And read verse 3 and 4.
It says
>> You don't have to guess, you can know.
Go ahead.
Let no man deceive you by any means. For
that day shall not come except there
come a falling away first, and that man
of sin be revealed, the son of
perdition. Uh-huh. Who opposeth and
exalteth himself above all that is
called God, or that is worshipped. So
that he as God sitteth in the temple of
God, showing himself that he is God. He
is not going to sit in the temple of
your mind. He going to sit in a physical
temple that will be built. So we have a
more sure word of prophecy. Daniel wrote
about it. They going to place the
abomination.
Jesus came and told you
he going to sit and then they going to
place the abomination. When you see this
thing, it's time to flee. And then
2nd to Paul told you
they going to sit in the temple and
profess himself to be God. You are going
to see this. It's going to happen.
That's all I got, Cornell.
All right. Thank you for that, brother.
Hope that answered their question as we
move on to our next one.
Moving on.
This comment might be funny, says my
confusion about the 2300 days and more
to do with the 1290 days and the 1335
days mentioned in Daniel 12. How do
these numbers fit into the prophecy?
2300, 1290, and 1335. Guest caller,
question is how do those numbers fit in
the prophecy.
You know,
you have some years, you have some days
that uh that fit, but the Bible don't
tell you where they fit. So, what you
got to do is deal with the absolutes.
First thing is
2,300 days includes the animal sacrifice
and the time that the Pope is going
sit in the temple. The time of 3 and 1/2
years. Let's go into Daniel 8 and read
verse 13 and 14.
Okay. Daniel 8 verses 13 and 14 say,
"Then I heard one saint speaking, and
another saint said unto that certain
saint which spake, how long shall be the
vision concerning the daily sacrifice
and the transgression of desolation to
give both the sanctuary and the host to
be trodden under foot?"
"And he said unto me, oh, mhm." Now,
now he asked a question. How long should
it be?
About if if it was the the
daily sacrifice and the transgression.
Rest of the uh be trodden under foot.
Let's talk about the time that he's
going to take uh
uh the animal sacrifice, the year, the
days, and also the days that the
abomination of desolation going to tread
the sanctuary under foot. That's where
it's going to be in Jerusalem in the
temple. And how many days? Go ahead.
"And he said unto me, unto 2,300
days, then shall the sanctuary be
cleansed."
Now, that includes from day one to
animal sacrifice until the last day
of the great tribulation.
2,300 days. So, when any of the days
fit, some people try to fit them in the
middle
and uh uh
use that saying that, well, you know,
he's going to take these many days for
the
Pope to move in after they have stopped
the sacrifice. The book don't say that.
Go to one place, last place, Daniel 11
and read verse 6 and 7.
Daniel 11 and verse 6 and 7 say,
"And in the end of years, they shall
join themselves together, for the king's
daughter of the south shall come to the
king of the north to make an agreement."
But she said, "Uh-huh." Wait a minute.
That's That's not what Daniel
That Daniel 11 is it 6 and 7?
Let's see.
Daniel 11
Mhm.
No, 12 6 and 7. I'm sorry. Okay.
Daniel 12 verses 6 and 7 say, "And one
said to the man clothed in linen, which
was upon the waters of the river, how
long shall it be to the end of these
wonders?
And I heard the man clothed in linen,
which was upon the waters of the river.
And when he held up his right hand and
his left hand unto heaven, and swear by
him that liveth forever, that it shall
be for a time, times, and a half, and
when he shall have accomplished to
scatter the power of the holy people,
all these things shall be finished."
So that's the whole thing. So now, the
2,300 days cover the animal sacrifice
and the time of the great tribulation.
Where are some of the other days? We
don't know where to put them, but we
know the overall picture.
When you see them build a temple in
Jerusalem, you better flee. When you see
the Pope move in it.
Because if you don't, you're going to
get caught in the great tribulation. But
before
uh uh uh uh
before that start, though, they're going
to have to start the animal sacrifice.
So,
some of the days some days are 30
minutes off with 45 days off. We
understand the whole thing, the
beginning and the end is over in 2,300
days.
That's all I have to say.
All right.
Hope that answered your question. And uh
sister Deborah, I'm next one with the
time check. Yes, the time is 8:06.
D. Law asked, "Was Father Adam the first
high priest?"
Was Father Adam the first high priest?
Brother Jerome.
No.
Adam ain't never been no high priest.
Uh
Jesus actually is the first high priest.
Okay?
Let's go to uh Hebrews 6.
Verse 20.
Okay.
Hebrews 6 and verse 20 says,
"Whether the forerunner is for us
entered, even Jesus made an high priest
forever after the order of Melchisedec."
Now, before he loaned the priesthood to
uh Aaron and his sons, Jesus was the
priest of the most high God already.
Yeah. Okay?
And that chapter 7 kind of lets you know
that, you know? So, let's look at
chapter 7, read verse 1, and skip and
read verse 3.
Okay.
It says, "For this Melchisedec, king of
Salem, priest of the most high God, who
met Abraham returning from the slaughter
of the kings and blessed him.
Verse three.
>> Verse three. Without father, without
mother, without descent, having neither
beginning of days nor end of life, but
made like unto the Son of God, abideth a
priest continually. And we know that we
we know that's Jesus. He ain't got no
beginning of days or end of life. He
ain't got no mother, no father.
Okay.
So, he was a priest long before Abraham
of the most high God.
That's all I got.
I'd like to make a statement. Okay.
>> Yes, sir.
A priest's job is to intercede for the
sinners.
Okay?
Yep.
So, now
Adam
before
So, in order for you to need an
intercessor
then have to be committed.
So, why would the Lord need
Adam to be a high priest if no sin had
been committed? Wow, good point.
That's all I have to say. Exactly.
>> All right.
Thank you for that add-on. Hope that
answered your question as we move on to
our next one.
Is sister Deborah with us? Uh we lost
sister Deborah. She dropped off.
>> So, we're going to move on to our next
question, which is from brother Israel
8487.
Please, can you explain what Luke 6 and
verse 27 through 35 is saying? Brother
Dre.
Yeah, let's go to Luke 6.
And we going to read we not going to
read all of it.
Uh
Luke 6:27
Start at verse
uh
Verse 20.
Okay.
Mhm. Luke 6:20 says, "And he lifted up
his eyes on his disciples and said,
'Blessed are ye poor, for yours is the
kingdom of God.
Mhm.
Blessed are ye that are hungry now.
That hunger now, for ye shall be filled.
Blessed are ye that weep now, for ye
shall laugh.
Blessed are ye
>> What What verse are you at now? That's
verse 21. Okay. Go ahead.
Blessed are ye when men shall hate you,
and when they shall separate you from
their company, and shall reproach you,
and cast out your name as evil for the
Son of man's sake.
Yes, and I skipped down to verse 27. Go
ahead.
But I say unto you which hear, "Love
your enemies, do good to them which hate
you. Mhm. Bless them that curse you, and
pray for them which despitefully use
you.
And unto Uh-huh.
So, what he's telling us is how we
should be as servants of God.
Skip down to verse 32. Go ahead.
For if ye love them which love you, what
thank ye What thank have ye?
For sinners also love those that love
them. Yes. And if ye do good to them
which do good to you, what thank have
ye? For sinners also do even the same.
Mhm. And if ye lend to them of whom ye
hope to receive, what thank have ye?
For sinners also lend to sinners to
receive as much again. So,
you're no different than a sinner if
you're doing
the things that people would do for you,
you do for them.
What makes you any different? But look
at what else he says. 35 and 36. Go
ahead.
But love ye your enemies and do good and
lend, hoping for nothing again, and your
reward shall be great. And ye shall be
the children of the highest, for he is
kind unto the unthankful and to the
evil.
Mhm.
Be ye therefore merciful as your father
also is merciful. So, he is trying to
put into our mindset the mindset that he
had
toward us to make us
like him. Now,
let's go to Romans 12 and I want you to
pick it up at verse 17.
And I'mma give you a few other
scriptures that you can go to on your
own and read that. The companion
scripture to Luke 6 and 27 is Matthew
5:43
to 48. It will say the same thing.
Okay? So, Matthew
I mean Romans 12, pick it up at verse
17.
It says, "Recompense to no man evil for
evil.
Provide things honest in the sight of
all men. Mhm.
If it be possible, as much as lieth in
you, live peaceably with all men." And
and with some of us it seems like it
ain't possible, but it's not possible by
our own strength. Sometimes we got to
call on the Lord for that.
To to have that mindset. Because we want
to take vengeance on those that come at
us. But, look at what else it says. Go
ahead.
Dearly beloved,
avenge not yourselves, but rather give
place unto wrath. For it is written,
vengeance is mine. I will repay, saith
the Lord.
Yep. Go ahead.
>> Therefore, if thine enemy hunger, feed
him. If he thirst, give him drink. For
in so much doing, thou shalt heap coals
of fire on his head. Mhm. Go ahead. Be
not overcome of evil, but overcome evil
with good. Now, in addition to what we
just read, on your own, you can read
Proverbs 25
21 and 22, Ephesians 4 31 and 32,
Colossians 3 12 and 13, and James the
second chapter, especially verse 13.
That's all I got.
All right. Thank you for that. Great.
And we hope that they go in and do check
those scriptures out for edification.
All right, sister Deborah. We're going
to move on to our next one. Uh yes. Next
one. Brother Anthony H have two
questions. One, what is Judaism and
where did it come from? And two, can you
shed some light on Matthew 11 verse 12?
What does it mean the kingdom of heaven
suffered violence and violence taken by
force?
All right. So, in that question, first
part, what is Judaism and where did it
come from? And then Matthew 11 and 12,
guest caller.
Yeah, well, you know, Judaism
is something that
that that was not among Israel.
Because those are the people that
studied the first five books of Moses.
And what happened is
uh
Our forefathers, the Hasmoneans, which
are called the Maccabees,
they had to conquer the certain area
when
when they was fighting with the Syrians.
And what happened was in that same area
was the nation of Idumea or either Edom
because they had moved down in southern
Jerusalem.
And what happened was
when they was fighting the Syrians, they
would come up through there and attack
the Jews. But but the Jews come up with
a good plan. They thought that they
said, "Well, they force all of the
people in that area,
mostly the Idumeans,
to start studying the five books of
Moses, you know, so they would use them
use religion as a protection."
Now,
there is, you know, I can go in there
and show you where he had people running
around called them with the with the
apostles, with the Pharisees and
Sadducees, called themselves the
Herodians. Because these was people
that was or Idumeans that had
been converted
to study the first five books of Moses,
which is called Judaism. Now, out of
these same
uh people that was converted
came Herod the Great.
Rome made Herod the Great
king of
Jerusalem.
And the people never never accepted it.
But to give you an idea, just give you a
brief thing. We don't have no Bible on
it, but I have a Bible a diff- a history
book that's called The Great
uh uh uh
People of the Bible.
I'm going to read you a little bit about
Herod.
I'm going to read you a little about
Herod the Great out of this
book that's called The Great People of
the Bible. You can go and You can go on
the internet and get it yourself if you
want a copy.
Now, it reads here.
See, because the Romans had had taken
over Judea.
And they needed somebody
that they could trust
to execute their law in Judea or
Jerusalem.
So, what they did was
they set a Jew over them. But they
didn't understand that this guy was not
a real Jew.
Now, I'm reading from
page 314.
The title is Herod the Great.
Rome needed a shrewd and capable agent
in Palestine.
And in Herod the Great
they felt they had found such a man.
Young, ambitious,
and brutal when necessary.
Herod was not a true Jew.
But an Idumaean
whose forefathers had been forced
to convert to Judaism
a century before.
Do not
When the Hasmoneans, which called uh uh
uh
Maccabees, converted these
the white people that called themselves
Jews was a That was
I say a hundred before Herod a hundred
years before Herod's time.
They start
They gave it the name Judaism.
It was started about 100 years before
uh uh 5 BC.
When the Hasmonean
converted the
to
the first five books of Moses cuz this
is all they studied till now.
That's what Judaism is. First five books
of Moses.
Mhm. Who gave it the name? The people
that call themselves Jews.
Not Israel.
And when did they get converted? I say
100 years before 5 BC.
That's that question.
Now the other one, when it says that the
kingdom of God suffered violence,
but we're going to make it brief.
All this saying is that the people
uh uh uh
the servants of God, the people that
represented the kingdom,
was killed and stoned
by Israel.
It's just like
Jesus was crucified at the behest of the
Pharisee.
John the Baptist
was killed
by Herod.
And look what Jesus say
concerning
the people that represent God. Go to
Luke 13 and read verse 34.
Okay.
Luke 13 and verse 34.
Where it says, "O Jerusalem, Jerusalem,
which killeth the prophets and stoneth
them that are sent unto thee. How
often would I have gathered thy children
together as a hen doth gather her
abroad under her wings, and ye would
not.
So, that's what it mean that suffer by
uh kingdom of God is suffer by violent.
The people that represent the kingdom of
God, they can't Can nobody put no hand
on the father's kingdom.
This is never.
But, the people that the Lord sent, they
stoned some of the prophets.
They killed some of them.
They killed John the Baptist. They
killed Jesus. And they killed people
after that.
And during the great tribulation,
they going to kill some more.
Men and women that represent
the kingdom of God.
That's all they saying.
That's all I have to say.
All right.
I hope that you was able to see that
light as we move on to our next
question.
Yes, next one. Kim will as,
why IOG don't do the Passover together
like Jesus did? Wouldn't it be easier
than giving to people on the way out?
So, Julius, why
don't we do the Passover like Jesus did?
Would it be easier to give it to the
people on the way out, brother?
First of all,
the Passover is a memorial. Let's go to
Matthew the sixth uh the 26th chapter.
We could take you to Exodus the 12th
chapter, Leviticus the 23rd chapter, but
let's get Let's look at Jesus did it.
And
let's look at what he did.
Matthew the 26th chapter, brother James.
We going to pick this up at verse 18 and
19. Why IOG don't do the Passover
together like Jesus did?
Let's see Let's see what uh what we did.
Let's see what Jesus did.
Matthew 26 and 18 and 19. Go ahead,
James.
And he said, "Go into the city to such a
man and say unto him, the master has the
master saith, my time is at hand. I will
keep the Passover at thine house with my
disciples." Uh-huh. And the disciples
did as Jesus had appointed them, and
they made ready the Passover.
Now, pick it up at verse 26.
Let's look at what Jesus did. Go ahead.
As they were eating, Jesus took bread
and blessed it and break it and gave it
to his to the disciples and said, "Take,
eat, this is my body." Now, when Jesus
came along,
the original Passover was kept with uh,
bitter herbs,
you know, and wine and and drink and uh,
represent the broken body of Jesus and
and and and the blood of Jesus. Okay?
So, he said, he he took bread and
blessed it and break it and gave it to
the disciples, "Take, eat, this is my
body." Now, we kept the Passover.
The Passover is the uh, first month, the
14th day of the of the of the month at
evening, which is sundown. We observed
that this year.
We had a holy convocation. We kept the
Passover. What else did Jesus do?
And he took the cup and gave thanks and
gave it to them saying, "Drink ye all of
it." Uh-huh. For this is my blood of the
new testament, which is shed for many
for the remission of sins. Now, the
first month, the 14th day of the month
at sundown, we took the bread and we ate
it with just the matzo crackers
representing the broken body of Christ.
Being we had the wine.
And on the on the way out, everybody ate
the bread and the wine. We kept the
Passover.
Sisters and brothers, we kept the
Passover. So, what is it different that
we did? Because we did it on the way
out, we still heard the message, we
broke the bread, and we cooked it and
and and
we drank the wine. We kept the Lord's
Passover just like he did. He just kept
it with his disciples.
But, it's still But, he told Israel down
in Egypt,
"Y'all keep it. Um every man and take a
lamb and the blood and everything and
all of that."
But, then Jesus came and did it the way
he told us to do it, and we kept it the
way he said. I don't see the problem.
Anybody else?
Uh that's it, brother. He's He said,
"Hey, do this in remembrance of me,
right?" And then he And that's what it
is, brother Cornell. That's what it is.
We did it in remembrance of him. He told
you at uh 1 Corinthians 5:7 that Christ,
our Passover, is sacrificed for us. So,
we And we did it in remember of his shed
blood and his broken body.
With the symbol that he gave us to do it
with. That's all I got.
Yes, sir. All right.
We hope that answered your question as
we move on to our next one. Next one,
Love Twice asks, "Are tortilla wraps
okay to eat during the week of
unleavened bread? They are made with
baking soda, which is a leavening agent,
but they are flat."
All right. We're talking about tortilla
wraps here, and they're flat, and they
got baking soda in them, but Brother
Julius, are they okay to eat during the
week of unleavened bread?
Uh the unleavened bread?
The baking soda in it also makes it
pliable, makes it flexible.
It makes the dough tender to roll.
It's It's more than just a leavening
agent. But,
what When I came across that situation,
I personally just got me a corn
tortilla.
I got me a corn tortilla that does not
have any leavening in it
at all.
So, to be safe, just do the corn
tortilla.
That's all I got, Cornell.
All right.
Yes, caller.
The The question is answered, said, "But
they are flat." But they are flat,
right.
Say that they are not leavened. They
have not risen.
I don't care what you have in it. If
it's flat, it is unleavened bread.
There you go.
So, leaven means to rise.
>> Okay?
You okay, D?
All right.
Hope that answered your question there,
sister Deborah. We going into new
territory. Yes, we are now into
tonight's Q&A for Wednesday, April the
8th, 2026.
The Bayou Perspective
says, "Brother Buie said you can eat
leaven bread on the Passover in the
past. Does this still apply today?"
All right. We're going to ask the guest
caller, can you represent Brother Buie
on this question?
Well,
Brother Buie ain't never said you can
eat leaven bread on the Passover.
But
Brother Buie
did say that after you eat the Passover,
the rest of the day you could eat
unleavened You could eat leavened bread,
which was wrong.
And we're going to go and look at this
because
sometime it takes
a a
certain understanding so you can know
whether you're doing something wrong or
not. Let's go to Exodus the 12th chapter
and we're going to look at something
here. Exodus 12:5-8.
Exodus 12
5 5 and 8 or 5 through 8, sir? 5 through
8. Okay.
Exodus 12:5 says, "Your lamb shall be
without blemish, a male of the first
year. Ye shall take it out of out from
the sheep or from the goats.
And ye shall keep it up
until the 14th day of the same month,
and a whole assembly of the congregation
of Israel shall kill it in the evening.
And they shall take of the blood and
strike it on the two side posts and on
the upper door posts of the houses
wherein they shall eat it.
They shall eat the flesh in that night
roast with fire and unleavened bread and
with bitter herbs they shall eat it.
So now that lets you know right there
that the Passover you have to be ate
with unleavened bread.
Yes.
But where brother Boorman made an error
error here
that he didn't see didn't understand the
depth of the Passover.
He thought he could take the Passover
and unleavened bread and then the next
day could eat leavened bread and then
once the first day of unleavened bread
come then you don't eat anymore for 7
days.
But actually if you include
the Passover
it would have been one day of unleavened
bread
and 7 days of one day of a Passover and
7 days of unleavened bread. Now, let me
show you that this conclusion was came
to once we looked at the spiritual part
of it.
And I remember Brother Buell called all
of his teachers together and the elders
and and and also showed it in the class
that
this error was an error and it was
corrected. Let me show you why it was an
error.
And now it will and because we didn't
get the spiritual understanding. So,
let's go to the 1st Corinthians the 5th
chapter the 5th chapter 5
verse 7 and 8.
Okay.
1 Corinthians chapter 5 verse 7 and 8
say
purge out therefore the old leaven
that ye may be a new lump as ye are
unleavened for even Christ our Passover
is sacrificed for us.
Therefore, therefore, let us keep the
feast not with old leaven, neither with
the leaven of malice and wickedness, but
with the unleavened bread of sincerity
and truth.
So, finally
Brother Buell come to the understanding
that once you eat the unleavened bread
that that represent purging out your
sin.
Now, you can't purge out your sin in
night and day and and for and then go
back to them for a little while and when
the 1 Corinthians and when the first day
of unleavened bread come, you go back
sin free.
So, Brother Buell had to come to the
conclusion that once you took that
unleavened that once you took your
Passover, you didn't eat any more
unleavened bread until the last till
after the 7th day of the feast of
unleavened bread was over with.
So, when you count 7 days of unleavened
bread,
one day passover is eight days.
So,
Brother Booth had made an error, and
Brother Booth corrected it.
That's all I have to say.
>> Yes, sir. Indeed. All right.
We appreciate that correction that was
made. All right.
We're going to continue to move on to
our next question.
Yes,
next question. Learning the truth asked,
"Is salvation for everyone?"
Yes, salvation is for everyone with some
rules and some regulations that go along
with it. Let's first pick this up in
Ecclesiastes the 12th chapter.
Ecclesiastes 12.
And when you get there, my brethren,
I want you to pick it up at verse
uh pick it up at that verse um
nine. Go ahead.
And moreover, because the preacher was
wise, he still taught the people
knowledge. Yea, he had he gave good heed
and sought out and set in order many
proverbs. Yeah, because you got to be
somewhere where you got to preach it and
know the book so they can teach you how
to be wise and get salvation. Read.
The preacher sought to find out
acceptable words, and that which was
written was upright, even words of
truth. Yes, and the words of truth are
in this book we are reading out of right
now. Go ahead.
The words of the wise are as goads, and
as nails fastened by the master of
assemblies, which are given from one
shepherd. And given from one shepherd,
which is the Lord gave this word, and we
are keeping it even unto this day. Skip
down, read 13 and 14 because this is for
every man, woman, and child that has
ever been born. Open salvation for
everybody. Go ahead.
Let us hear the conclusion of the whole
matter.
Fear God and keep his commandments for
this is the whole duty of man. You keep
them commandments and fear God, hey, and
salvation is wide open for you. Verse
14.
For God shall bring every work into
judgment with every secret thing,
whether it be good or whether it be
evil. Yes, cuz you'll be held
accountable for everything good or evil.
So, you keep the commandments so you can
walk right please God. Go to Isaiah 56
right quick and we got one more after
that. Isaiah 56.
Okay. And this is after the Lord is
back. Isaiah 56, read that verse 6 and 7
for me. Go ahead.
Also, the sons of the stranger that join
themselves to the Lord to serve him and
to love the name of the Lord to be his
servants, everyone that keepeth the
Sabbath from polluting it and taking
hold of my covenant. Uh-huh.
Even them will I bring to my holy
mountain and make them joyful in my
house of prayer. Their burnt offerings
and their sacrifices shall be accepted
upon my altar for mine house shall be
called an house of prayer for all
people. Oh, for all people upon earth.
So, yeah, this salvation is open for
everybody upon earth.
When you keep these commandments and
walk with the Lord. Matthew 28 and 18
to 20 and that'll be it. Matthew 28.
And pick it up at that verse 18.
And let's see who the Lord said go out
to and talk to.
Go ahead.
And Jesus came and spake unto them
saying, "All power is given unto me in
heaven and in earth." Yep. Go ye
therefore and teach all nations,
baptizing them in the name of the Father
and of the Son and of the Holy Ghost.
Teaching all nations wherever man,
woman, or child is at. Read 20.
Teaching them to observe all things
whatsoever I have commanded you. And lo,
I am with you always, even unto the end
of the world. Amen. Amen. So yes,
salvation is open for everyone, but you
have to obey the Lord, you have to keep
his commandments, and love him, and do
what he say, and salvation will belong
to you.
That's all I got.
I want to throw in something. Yes, sir.
You going to Revelation the fifth
chapter?
You in Revelation the fifth chapter?
Father was sitting on a throne with a
book in his hand.
And it said that no
body
could read that
unseal or read that book in in in heaven
and in earth or under the earth.
And John started to weep.
But the angel told John to weep not
because the lion of the tribe of Judah
can open the book.
Yep.
>> And read what
So, we going to pick it up where the
lion of Judah is going to going to get
take the book out of the Father's hand.
In Revelation 5, start reading at verse
7.
Okay.
>> to it.
By
Go ahead.
>> It says, "And he came and took the book
out of the right hand of him that sat
upon the throne.
And when he had taken the book, the four
beasts and four and 20 elders fell down
before the lamb, having every one of
them harps and golden vials full of
odors, which are the prayers of saints.
And they sang
And they sung a new song saying, "Thou
art worthy to take the book and to open
the seals thereof. For thou was slain
and has redeemed us to God by thy blood
out of every kindred and tongue and
people and nation."
And has
Go ahead.
And has made us unto our God kings and
priests and we shall reign on the earth.
So not only is he going to have people
saved out of every kindred, tongue, and
nation,
they going
These people that's talking here is in
the first resurrection.
And these
people out of every kindred, tongue, and
nation is going to help Jesus, along
with us, rule this earth for a thousand
years. Yes, sir.
>> Yeah, that look like
salvation to me.
Yes, sir.
All right. Thank you for that add-on and
we hope that that answered your
question, Sister Deborah. Next question,
please.
>> Yes, next question. Surely as W says,
when the Most High judges a nation, its
leaders seems to, in a way, go crazy or
insane before judgment. Am I wrong?
All right, we'd like to take a crack at
that one first.
When the Most High judges
>> Because they saying when the Most High
judges a nation, its leaders seem to go
crazy or insane before judgement. Am I
wrong?
Well, you know, you got
uh
Nebuchadnezzar
You know, he had to eat straw, but the
Lord had him do that.
And then he restored him.
And he acknowledged that the Lord was in
control.
Right.
You know, but uh
Yeah, and there are examples, but
also he he did
Go ahead, guest caller.
Or you can say the Lord set up nation
and he take down nation. That's right.
>> do that.
And whether they What does the scripture
say that? And whether they go crazy or
not, we ain't got nothing written on
that. There you go. I think
I I think this one we have to leave
alone.
Yes, sir.
All right. We're going to move on to our
next question. And next one, she also
asked, "My question pertains to the
Antichrist,
son of perdition, and the beast.
There are others, but can't recall them.
Are they the same person or different
people?"
Let's open that up to the panel. Um
she says some shady areas on that
question about What was the What was the
second half of that question, Deborah?
Are they the same
Are they the same person or different
people? Antichrist, son of perdition,
and the beast.
Well, the ones that they're talking
about, the Bible talk about, is not You
know, you got a lot of Antichrist.
And you got a lot of guys with the
uh behave like beast. But the Bible is
talking about two people. The one that's
called a false prophet and the one
that's called the beast.
Which is going to be
political leader or temporary leader of
the European Union.
Now, the Lord is going to deal with them
two of them. Go to Revelation the 19th
chapter.
And
this is the coming of the Lord. I think
it start about where it say in
They going
make war with the lamb.
Verse 19. Mhm. Okay.
19 and 19, read it.
It says, "And I saw the beast and the
kings of the earth and their armies
gathered together to make war against
him that sat on the horse and against
his army.
And the beast was taken with him the
false prophet and wrought miracles
before him
with which he deceived them that had
received the mark of the beast and them
that worshipped his image. These both
were cast alive into a lake of fire
burning with brimstone."
Mhm. Now,
these are the two guys.
Uh one's called the beast and the one's
called the false prophet. I don't use
the word Antichrist
because it's too nebulous. That's covers
a whole lot of stuff. I use what the
what the Bible use, the beast and the
false prophet.
And these are two individuals that's
going to be around when Jesus come.
And he going to cast both of them in the
lake of fire that is coming.
That's all I have to say.
Forever.
All right. We hope that that answered
your question as we continue to move on
to our next
Our next one. Kylie Parker says in
Exodus 16 verse 12, it specifies
no chores on this feast. But my family
was wondering if it's okay to do dishes
on this day, or was this verse only
specifying to clean up dishes used for
this feast?
So, Exodus 16 verse 12.
All right, let's go there and see if
that
matches up with the question. Let's go
to Exodus 16 and 12, brother, and after
you read it, let's open it up to the
panel.
Okay. Exodus 16 and 12 says, "I have
heard the murmuring of the children of
Israel. Speak unto them saying, at
evening you shall eat flesh, and in the
morning you shall be filled with bread,
and you shall know that I am the Lord
your God."
Okay, so where is the dishes part
in that question?
Or the feast.
>> [gasps]
>> Or the feast. So,
um because we don't see it there, and no
one in the panel has addressed that, we
ask you to resubmit it and put a little
more detail in it so that we can be a
little more certain of where you're
coming from on that question.
So, all right, sister Deborah, we're
going to move on to our next Next one,
Amazing Israel, uh Israelite asked,
"What is the difference between the
gathering of the nations after
Armageddon and the great white throne
judgment?"
Gathering and white throne after
Armageddon, let's open that up to the
panel, too.
Well, the whole thing is, Armageddon
is when the Lord's going to come,
and he is going to bring all nations
down into the valley of Megiddo.
Yep.
>> That's why it's called Armageddon.
And that is north
west of Jerusalem.
It's going to be World War III.
And that's the gathering of
And it tell you that and and and
tell you that he going to do that I
think it's
Joel Go Joel 3 and 1.
I think that and start reading. Let's
see what it's all about.
Is it Joel 3 and
Joel 3 and 1.
Joel 3 and 1 says
For behold, in those days and in that
time when I shall bring again the
captivity of Judah and Jerusalem.
I will also gather all nations and will
bring them down into the valley of
Jehoshaphat and will plead with them
there for my people and for my heritage
Israel.
Whom they have scattered among the
nations and parted my land.
The Lord letting you know that in the
days that he's going to get before he
get ready to bring Israel in same days
he's going to bring all nations down
to the valley of Jehoshaphat. That's
where Jehovah Jehovah will judge or
either
the valley of Megiddo.
And he's going to take them all down at
one time.
And once he do that he's going to take
the world over and rule it for a
thousand years, this earth.
And at the end of the thousand years
he's going to let
at the beginning of the thousand years
he is going to
put
take Satan out of action. He's going to
bind him. And at the beginning and at
the end of the thousand years he's going
to loose Satan.
Satan is going to go out to all the
world. And you're still going to have
some people that's going to follow him.
Then fire going to come down from God
and kill those cuz they going to go up
on the camp of the saints and try to
attack Jesus
and the people in the first
resurrection.
But fire going to come down
heaven
and destroy
the army
and and kill the people. He going to
throw Satan in the lake of fire.
Then he going to have the white throne
judgment. So the gathering of the
nations and the white throne judgment is
over a thousand years apart. That's all
I had to say.
All right.
Thank you for that. Hope that answered
your question as we move on to our next
one with the time check. Yes, the time
is 8:48. Uh this question was uh
uh answered
uh talking about the unleavened bread,
but Shaniqua Akujobi
asked
for the unleavened bread, was it
mandatory to keep eating it after the
Passover or was it only required during
the Passover itself?
It was required during the the Passover
itself, the 7 days, but it's also okay
to eat it afterwards.
I mean it still tastes good with peanut
butter on it. Anybody on the panel?
All right. So yeah, you have to eat it
through during the 7 days of unleavened
bread and um
after that's over, it's okay to still
eat it after
unleavened bread is over.
All right, Sister Deborah, our next one.
Next one, More Muddy Waters asks, "What
is the difference between the Father and
God in prayers? I know they are
different, but whom do you pray to for
forgiveness or like something specific?
Matthew
>> let's open that up to the panel. Looks
like brother Julius Chamblee in first.
What you got, brother?
Matthew 6th chapter.
I'm there.
And we begin reading at verse 13.
Okay. Matthew 6 and 13 says,
"And lead us not into temptation, but
deliver No, start it out with I'm sorry.
Start it out with our father.
Okay.
Mhm.
Verse 9. Yep. Our
after this manner, therefore, pray ye.
Now, Jesus is telling you who to pray
to.
After this manner, pray you. Go ahead.
Our Father, which art in heaven.
Hallowed be thy name.
Thy kingdom come. Thy will be done in
earth as it is in heaven. There you go.
So, that's enough That's enough of that.
So, when you pray, Jesus said, "When you
pray, pray on this way. You don't pray
to me. You pray to the Father in my
name."
So, because he is our intercessor.
That's all I got.
You got to understand the rule.
You pray to the Father,
but also it have to be in Jesus' name
because Jesus is the high priest. Yes,
sir. And the high priest the one that
intercede for you.
That is the order of things like it was
with Melchizedek. Or it was with Elijah.
When you wanted to go and and
you sinned, the high priest had to go
and sprinkle the blood
before the veil.
Do the same thing. You go to the Father,
the high priest. I think it's in the 1
John the 2nd chapter, I think. See if
you can read and start at verse 1. Say
if we sin, we have an advocate. Yes.
Thank you for
2 and 1.
Yes, it is. Yes, it Yes, it is, sir.
It says, 1 John 2 and 1 says, "My little
children, these things write I unto you
that ye sin not."
"And if any man sin, we have an advocate
with the Father, Jesus Christ the
righteous."
Now, the advocate is the high priest.
He's the one that's going going plead
your cause.
So, you don't ever pray to Jesus.
You pray to the Father in Jesus' name.
Yes, sir.
All right. Amen.
All right. Praise the Lord.
Okay, we're going to move on to our next
question. Next one, Tiana Freezing asks,
"Is it okay to stay home from church
after having a baby if doctors recommend
a man avoiding public spaces until the
baby is about 2 months old and
vaccinated? So, is it okay to stay at
home from church?"
Yes, it is.
Yeah.
Yeah, it's okay to stay home. Tune in
with us on the Sabbath day and watch the
lesson, but it's okay to stay home.
All right.
Our next question. Next one, Orlando
Davie asks, "In Genesis 25:23
and Genesis 27:40,
is Esau to regain his birthright?"
>> [laughter]
>> Yeah.
He sold that birthright, but let's go to
Genesis 25.
Mhm. And 23, we'll go open this up also
to the panel.
And ask about regaining that birthright,
right? Uh Deborah?
Uh yes. Uh to regain his birthright.
All right. This is talking about the two
nations in the womb.
Genesis 25:17-23.
Uh pick it up at 22, brother, and we'll
um open it up to the panel.
Okay. It says, "And the children
struggled together within her. And she
said, 'If it be so, why am I thus?' And
she went to inquire of the Lord."
"And the Lord said unto her, 'Two
nations are in thy womb. And two manner
of people shall be separated from thy
bowels. And the one people shall be
stronger than the other people. And the
elder shall serve the younger.'"
Mhm.
"And when her days to be delivered
Uh
Now
Now now that within itself lets you know
that Esau is not going to regain his
birthright. Because the Lord have
already said who is going to serve who
before either one of us born.
So for Esau to make to sell his
birthright, that just
that that was merely a
legalization.
But the birthright had already been
given to Jacob before they was born.
That's why I said the elder shall serve
the younger.
So no, he ain't going to regain no
birthright.
Plus when you read ver- read verse 34.
>> 33 uh uh
33? Or it started at 33? Yeah. Okay.
It says, "And Jacob said, 'Swear to me
this day.' And he swore unto him, and he
sold his birthright unto Jacob." Mhm.
"Then Jacob gave Esau bread and pottage
of lentils, and he did eat and drink,
and rose up and went his way. Thus, Esau
despised his birthright. He despised his
birthright.
Wow.
Huh.
Yeah. Wow.
You despised it, you didn't want it. All
right.
That's um
at Genesis 27:40 was a question, too,
right, Deborah? Yes.
Let's go there, brother James. Let's
read that one.
And uh share some light on that and then
we can move from there.
Okay.
Genesis 27:40 says, "And by the sword
shalt thou live, and shalt serve thy
brother. And it shall come to pass when
thou shalt have the dominion that thou
shalt break his yoke from off thy neck."
Okay.
Um I think we pretty
>> no, he ain't he's not he's not No.
He won't get it back. He sold it. No,
and and and one more place, man. Go to
Hebrews 12 and read verse 16.
Yes, sir. That is it, brother.
Hebrews 12 16 and 17, yeah.
>> And verse 16 and 17 says,
"Lest there be any fornicator or profane
person, as Esau, who for one morsel of
meat sold his birthright. Mhm.
For ye know how that afterward, when he
would have inherited the blessing, he
was rejected.
For he found no place of repentance,
though he sought it carefully with
tears." Wow.
So, yeah, he ain't he ain't got nothing
coming on that.
No.
No, that's over and done with. All
right.
Sister Deborah, we are approaching our
time, but let's go to another question
here.
All right. Marjorie Greer
says, "Brother Bowie mentioned that the
unleavened cakes during the current
feast looked as the cakes had risen."
Does that mean we should not prepare
cakes for the feast, even if we are not
using leavening agents?
>> [snorts]
>> All right, we're going to ask the guest
caller again and see if he can represent
Brother Bowie on this question here.
I think he's uh taking a phone call
right now.
Oh, okay.
So, Sister Deborah, can you read that
one more time? Yes.
Uh
Brother Bowie mentioned that the
unleavened cakes during the current
feast looked as the cakes had risen.
Does that mean we should not prepare
cakes for the feast, even if we are not
uh
even if we are not using
leavening agents?
Yeah, I think that was mentioned.
Uh that
>> Bowie
Yeah, so
um guest caller, can you represent
Brother Bowie on this question?
So, state that again.
Right. Uh Brother Bowie mentioned that
the unleavened cakes during the current
feast looked as the cakes had risen.
Does that mean we should not prepare
cakes for the feast, even if we are not
using leavening agents?
Listen, I'mma say this one more time. It
don't have nothing to do with leavening
agents. It has something to do did it
rise or not?
And all the cakes I've seen rose.
So,
this is not resonating.
It is not the feast of unleavened
agents. It is the feast of unleavened
bread, unrisen
bread.
So, all the cakes I've seen and the
cookies I've seen are not flat like it
was when you put them on the grill.
Unleavened mean if it is if it is an
eighth of an inch when it's raw
and once you cook it, it's still an
eighth of an inch, that is unleavened.
But if you put it down there an eighth
of an inch thick dough
and when it cooks
it's an inch
it is leavened.
And somebody just told me
called me and told me about some kind of
tortilla
wrapping. So, that's leavened, too.
Look,
if it rise at all, it is leavened.
Leavened mean to rise. So, yeah,
these cakes I've seen, all of them are
leavened.
I've even seen some
cornbread that was cooked.
It was leavened. If it is not the same
thickness that it was
when it's raw and you pour it in the
plate, it is leavened. Got nothing to do
with agents.
It is the feast of unleavened
bread.
Not the feast of unmixed
un
uh uh uh
ingredients. Yes.
Uh ingredients, you know, like you got
the baking soda and all. It means
nothing.
Unleavened, unrisen.
That's all I got to say.
All right.
Thank you for that. Hope that answered
their question. Sister Deborah, time
check. Yes, the time is 9:02.
9:02. We have ran out of time and we
want to thank everybody from all around
the world who joined us this evening.
We had fun sitting down with you doing
our question and answer. And we'd like
to say if you submitted a question we
didn't get to it, please don't resubmit
it. Sister Deborah take it, put it in
rotation and we will deal with that
question next Wednesday.
So we want to thank you all. And we say
until we all come together, be safe,
be blessed, stay prayed up, and the
whole panel here wishes everyone
a happy unleavened bread
for the second night.
All right. Brother James, can you close
us out?
Our Father, which art in heaven,
hallowed be thy name. Thy kingdom come,
thy will be done in Earth as it is in
heaven.
Give us this day our daily bread and
forgive us our debts as we forgive our
debtors. And lead us not into
temptation, but deliver us from evil.
For thine is the kingdom and the power
and the glory forever. In Jesus' name we
pray. Amen.
Amen.